好的 准备欣赏下一场演示 Warudo
All right, get ready for our next presentation, Warudo,
一款可交互的 易用的直播动捕软件
Interactive and Accessible Live Performance Capture,
由Tiger Tang, Jesse Thompson
和Chelsey Kekahuna-Kalaukoa为大家呈现
presenting our Tiger Tang, Jesse Thompson, and Chelsey Kekahuna-Kalaukoa.
Tiger创办了Hakuya Labs
Tiger founded Hakuya Labs
并开发了Warudo这款开创性的虚拟主播3D直播软件
and developed Warudo, a pioneering 3D VTubing platform,
迅速赢得全球赞誉 并与各大虚拟艺人组织者建立合作关系
quickly earning global acclaim and partnerships with VTubing leaders
Phase Connect: 一家位于加拿大温哥华的英日虚拟YouTuber社团
异世界女团(Isegye Idol): 2021年成立的韩国虚拟女子偶像组合
包括Phase Connect和异世界女团
such as Phase Connect and Isegye Idol.
他的研究成果"虚拟形象表情与主播的松散耦合"
His work on loose avatar-streamer coupling for expressive VTubing
为他赢得了ISMAR 2021年度最佳学生论文奖
earned him the Best Student Paper award at ISMAR 2021.
Jesse 约翰·伯恩斯医学院解剖成像技术总监
Jesse, Technical Director of Anatomical Imaging at the John A. Burns School of Medicine,
拥有Frostic美术学院学士学位
holds a BA from the Frostic School of Fine Art
和夏威夷大学学习设计与技术硕士学位
and a Master's in Learning Design & Technology from the University of Hawaii.
他是VToku和XRLabs的联合创始人 专攻实时3D和医疗培训
He co-founded VToku & XRLabs, specializing in real-time 3D and medical training.
Chelsey是一名虚拟主播 也是VToku的联合创始人
Chelsey is a virtual performer & co-founder of VToku,
为其他虚拟直播人才提供技术咨询和项目运营服务
providing technical consulting & project management services to other virtual talents.
专攻实时3D工作流程和事件协调
Specializing in real-time 3D workflows & event coordination.
Brave Group: 一家主营虚拟YouTuber业务的企业
田中姬铃木雏就是该企业旗下的艺人
Chelsey的职业是Brave Group美国分部的人才总监
Chelsey works professionally as the Talent Director for Brave Group USA.
掌声有请三位!
Give it up for Tiger, Jessie and Chelsey.
白夜Tira
好的 各位晚上好 我叫Tiger
All right, good evening everyone, my name's Tiger,
今天我们将向大家演示我们的虚拟主播平台 Warudo
and today we're going to showcase our Vtubing platform, Warudo.
先给不了解虚拟主播的人介绍一下 这是一种时下流行的娱乐直播媒介
So for those who don't know anything about Vtubing, it's a popular live entertainment medium,
像Chelsey这样的内容创作者在舞台上以虚拟形象现身
where content creators like Chelsey onstage who embody virtual avatars,
并在Twitch与YouTube等平台向观众们进行在线直播
and they will stream to an online audience on platforms like Twitch or Youtube.
而3D虚拟主播内容产出成本通常十分高昂
So 3D Vtubing content is typically very expensive to produce,
例如像演唱会那样一小时的演出 可能要花费数千美元
so in one-hour performance or like a concert, can cost several thousand dollars,
成本包括动捕棚 数据后期处理 渲染等环节
including mo-cap studio, data post processing, rendering, etc.
但有了Warudo 3D直播变得简单且低成本 我们是如何做到的?
But with Warudo, it's accessible and affordable, and let's see how.
画面上展示的是用户使用Warudo时的蓝图设定界面
So right over there, we have Warudo with consumer facing VR tracking set up on the stage.
这里使用的是索尼的Mocopi追踪器 动捕服与手套 如果大家好奇的话
This is actually Sony's Mocopi trackers and plus dress and gloves, if you are curious.
如大家所见 对于创作者来说 这就像玩VR游戏一样
As you can see, there's a little bit like playing VR games for the creator,
但并不用戴头显 而是用手机捕捉面部表情
but instead of wearing a headset, they will use their smartphone to track their faces.
所以麻烦您做几个表情——好的
So if you can make some faces for us, all right.
另外 AR追踪也能让我们使用虚拟摄影师 就像现在的Jesse一样
And, um, AR tracking also enables us to have a virtual cameraman, like Jesse,
这样 在朋友的协助下 主播在家就能举办一场虚拟演唱会
so you'll be able to hold a virtual concert at home with your friends.
Warudo支持将经济实惠又便携的动作捕捉融合在一起
Warudo supports blending affordable and portable motion capture like this,
助力新一代的内容创作者
empowering this brand new generation of content creators.
虚拟主播直播的关键在于与观众的互动
The key to Vtubing is really the interaction with the audience,
与粉丝们一起创造令人难忘的特殊时刻
creating engaging and special moments with your fans.
Warudo提供了一个易于使用的可视化编程系统
We provide an easy to use visual programming system right here
只需拖动这些卡片即可实现复杂的逻辑行为
that allows you to design complex interventions by simply dragging notes.
这里举一个简单的例子
So for example, here's a very similar example.
比如说……我按下一个按键 比如Esc键
Let's say  um … when I press a key, let's say I press Esc key,
就会向我的角色投掷道具 然后把两张卡片连接起来 选择好"目标角色"
I will throw a prop at my character, and then you connect the notes, you select the character …
呃……这里还要选好"道具源"……选哪个呢? 大家喜欢猫猫还是狗狗?
Um … Maybe I'll select the Prop Source here … I don't know which one you guys prefer … Cat? Dog?
行吧 那就选猫猫!
All right, cat! Cat it is. All right!
这样 当我按下Esc时 诶嘿~
And when I press Esc key now, there you go.
我可以生成很多……抱歉Chelsey 只是用来做技术演示XD
And I just spawn this uh … Sorry Chelsey, but this is only for technical demonstration purposes.
我们还可以配置……比如"碰撞粒子源"
Um … And we can also configure something like , you know, impact particles,
还可以配置"碰撞音效源" 从而给猫猫更有打击感的视效和音效
so, and also a large sound so it can actually give you like a punch songs like that.
还可以这样 我们不去按Esc键
So now imagine, instead of pressing Esc key,
触发事件可以改为 比如收到了YouTube的赞助
you can replace this with something like, oh, when I receive a donation from Youtube, right?
比如YouTube直播中收到了礼物或会员订阅
When I receive a gift membership from Youtube,
或者比如有人在你的Twitch频道上兑换了频道点数 对吧?
or something like, oh, someone uh … redeems a channel bits uh … redeem on Twitch, right?
总之 软件是非常的顶……丁…… 高度定制化的!
So this is very customis … uh customisi … uh uh OK, this is very high customization. OK.
我们再来演示一个内容
So here we will demonstrate another one.
让我先启用一下这里的姿态蓝图
Enable … Let me enable this gesture blueprint right here.
这里四张卡片的逻辑大致是这样的
So right here, we have four notes that do basically like this.
当我的角色检测到做某个动作的时候 软件就切到主摄像机
So when I detect character is doing this gesture, I will switch the camera to the main camera.
当角色做一个"竖大拇指"的手势时 就切换到"Ipad摄像机"
And if they do another "Thumbs Up" gesture, that will switch the camera to the "Ipad Camera".
对吧? 嗯 您能为大家演示一下吗?
Right? So … yep! Can you demonstrate that for us?
好 成了
All right, it works.
还有一个蓝图演示
And here's another blueprint example.
这个蓝图大致逻辑是…… 如果我的右手与左手相接触
Um … So this one right here, it basically says, okay, um, when my right hand is in contact with my left hand,
就触发"SIGGRAPH球"这张卡片 并生成对应的粒子
I will toggle the "SIGGRAPH Ball" and spawn a particle.
走你
There you go.
相信大家能想到无数种可以组合的有趣玩法与特效
All right, as you can imagine, there are tons of ways you can combine these notes to create fun and original effects.
我们真的很惊讶能看到……
We've been really amazed at what the …
我还能再变一次
Well, it can do that trick again.
看 球又变没了
And yep, it goes away.
我们真的很惊讶能看到虚拟主播社区使用我们的可视化编程系统
Yeah. We'll been really amazed at what the Vtubing community has been able to create and share
在不需要雇佣开发者的情况下能创造并分享如此多的内容
with our visual programming system without the need to hire a developer.
找专业人士制作3D直播的成本可能高达每小时数百至数千元美元
For professionals, production costs of 3D performances can be hundreds to thousands per hour.
但有了Warudo 创作者们可以使用成本更低的VR追踪器与手机APP
But with Warudo, creators can get started with affordable VR trackers and phone apps.
同时软件还适配更专业的光学动捕系统 如Vicon和OptiTrack
And still have support for more professional performance capture solutions like Vicon or OptiTrack down the road.
现在 我想有请大家参与进来 如果大家对左上角的二维码好奇的话
Now, we would like you, the audience to participate, if you're curious about the QR code,
欢迎拿出手机扫描二维码 我将把舞台交给Chelsey
feel free to take out your phone, scan that one, and then I will leave the stage to Chelsey.
大家好呀 SIGGRAPH的各位!
Hello! There's so many of you here at SIGGRAPH.
大家感觉如何? 喜欢这样的实时3D直播吗?
How are you doing? How are you enjoying real time live?
大家扫描二维码了吗? 你会看到一个小窗口 里面有很多按钮
Well, you heard the man? Please scan that QR code, and you're going to see a little bit pop up with a bunch of buttons.
愿意的话 可以随意骚扰台上的我
Feel free to spam that away if you'd like.
好吧 倒也不至于这么热情
Well, okay, well maybe not spam that much.
好好好 谢谢大家 这功能相当正常
Okay. Thank you. It's definitely working.
作为内容创作者 我们都想要有最好的镜头和画面
So as content creators, we want to make sure that we have the best shots and the best images.
因此 在这个实时3D直播的现场 我们想为大家做一件非常特别的事情
And so here at real time live, we wanted to do something very special for you.
几分钟 或者说几秒钟后 大家会看到一个投票
So you're going to see a poll in just a few minutes, or a few seconds actually.
会有几个数字代表大家看到的不同的摄像——机——位
And it's going to have a couple of numbers dedicated to you the different cam—era—
正直播呢! 大伙!
We're on stream! Hello!
你们将成为我直播时的摄影师
You're going to be my cinematographer as I live.
那么——投票开始!
So start voting!
开始切镜头吧!
Change that camera.
感谢大家!
Thank you everyone.
感谢各位出色的摄影师和Chelsey在舞台上的互动
Thank you everyone for your amazing cinematographer and interaction with Chelsey on stage.
这就是我们的演示 谢谢大家!
And … yeah! That's our demo. Thank you everyone.